

Sukesh Batchu

Senior Frontend Developer

Phone: (+49) 17635 844116 | Email: sukeshkumarb@gmail.com | Linkedin: Linkedin: Address: Ahrweiler Str 26, 14197, Berlin, Germany

Summary

A highly committed Frontend responsive UI developer with experience of more than 7.5 years in the field of software development. Diligent in formulating best coding practices for the Frontend Development using trending and robust Frontend frameworks.

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology

Osmania University, India 2006 to 2010

Key Skills

Frontend

HTML5
CSS3
Bootstrap 4
Jquery, Jquery UI
Kendo UI
Angular Js, Angular 2+
Ext Js
Microsoft Sharepoint
React (Naive)
Electron JS

Tools

Sketch
Balsamiq
HPQC
Jira
BPM Tools
Tableau
Qlikview
Phonegap

Misc

Git
Webpack
Wordpress
Unbounce
Opentext
Scrum Agile Methodology
SEO

Experience

1. Senior Frontend Developer @ KPMG

Berlin

05.2015 - Till Date

2017 - Till date

- Development of responsive web applications using Sharepoint Customizations
- Delivered more than 7 applications working alone viz: Seat Planning, Event Registration Sites, Collaboration portals, Enterprise Search, Billing & Accounting Tool
- Primary focus on Angular 2+, Kendo for Angular, Bootstrap 4

2015 - 2016

- Development of responsive Frontend User Interfaces in .net environment
- Part of developing Immigration Tool, Reporting tool for Global Mobility team in Tax
- Primary focus on Angular JS, Kendo UI, Bootstrap 3
- 2. Senior Frontend Developer @ enadCo

Berlin

01.2015 - 04.2015

- Development of product user interfaces, maintaining the website, creation of Mobile User Interfaces
- 3. Senior Frontend Developer @ Accenture

India

01.2014 - 12.2014

- Involved in the development of Frontend for Bank of America Financial Products to migrate traditional UI to Rich Look Responsive UI using Ext JS
- 4. Software Developer @ Cognizant Technology Solutions Belgium, India 07.2010 12.2013

2010 - 2012

 Worked on BPM Tool called Cordys, involved in creating workflows, implementation of Web services.

2012 - 2013

 Part of Mobile Application Development team, involved in creating Hybrid Mobile Applications using Phonegap, Titanium Appcelerator

Sukesh Batchu Berlin, Germany